Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention, 1967-1968; VI.
  - Home Rule, 9.
    - Pamphlets, Reports and Editorials
      - Local and National Articles on Home Rule, 1966-1970 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Efforts to Implement the Judiciary, 10.
    These are the detailed files associated with efforts to promote and implement, in this case, the judiciary article. The news articles and files cover 1967-1968 with strong, organized efforts prior to the May 1968 primary. Thornburgh's files from the Pennsylvania Bar Association Committee on Implementation of Judiciary Article are particularly detailed, especially the Sub-Committee on Community Courts of which he was Chairman. There is additional information from the Allegheny County Bar Association as well as post Con Con speaking engagements and efforts by a Lawyers Committee for "Yes" vote. There are in depth reports pre primary and related post primary victory celebrations. Finally there are two files of historical interest, one a report by Mercer Tate from Con Con, in progress, and a "Con Con History" by George Wolf, published by the National Municipal League in 1969.
    - Bar Associations
      - "Project Constitution": Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1962-1966 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Revision Committee: Allegheny Bar Association, 1967, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 2-3)
      - PA Bar Association Committee on Implementation of Judiciary Article, Part I, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - PA Bar Association Committee on Implementation of Judiciary Article, Part I: Sub-Committee on Community Courts, Thornburgh Chairman, 1963-1969 (Box 30, Folder 5-7)
      - PA Bar Association Committee on Implementation of Judiciary Article, Part II, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 8-9)
      - Clippings regarding judiciary matters, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - PA Bar Association Committee on Implementation of Judiciary Article, "Report of the Subcommittee on Community Courts," Richard L. Thornburgh, Chairman, September 27, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Pre and Post Primary 1968 Actions and Results
      - Post Con Con Speaking Engagements and Lawyers Committee for "Yes" vote (pre-primary and including election results), March-May, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - "A Review of Judiciary Article Proposed by PA Constitutional Committee," Thornnburgh speech to PA Bar Association House of Delegates, March 22, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Pre Primary Promotions to Vote from various political and business people, March-May, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - In depth committee reports (pre-primary) (4), April, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - Con Con Proposals Passed: Primary, May, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - Memos post primary; victory celebration, May-June, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - Statement of RLT before the Judiciary Committee of the Senate of PA, October 23, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Con Con History
      - Reports from Con Con by Mercer Tate, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - "Constitutional Revision in Pennsylvania: The Dual Tactic of Amendment and Limited Convention," by George D. Wolf, published by National Municipal League, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Working Copies of Manuals, Proposals and Hearings, 11.
    This section documents delegate proposals, and history of proposals, including Thornburgh's working manuals. There is much material from public hearings before various committees, including especially the presentations before the Judiciary Committee, some with Thornburgh annotations. The public hearings before the Committee on Legislative Apportionment also contain his annotations.
    - Delegate Proposals 1000-1209: including 1000 and 1138 by Thornburgh, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Convention Calendar and History of Proposals, with indexes to proposals and resolutions, February 29, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Thornburgh's reference manuals (1-9) annotated, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Thornburgh's Proposals Adopted: working manuals, history and indexes, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention Public Hearings Before the Committee on the Judiciary, December 27,1967 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention Public Hearings Before the Committee on Local Government, December 28, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention Public Hearings Before the Committee on Taxation and State Finance, December 29, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention Public Hearings Before the Committee on Legislative Apportionment (annotated), December 29, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention Presentation Before the Committee on the Judiciary (annotated), January 4, 1968 and January 5, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention Presentation Before the Committee on the Judiciary, January 9, 1968 and January 11, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Constitutional Convention Publications, 12.
    These volumes are official and inclusive accounts of the convention: debates and journals of the convention, reference manuals, and proposals adopted by the convention.
    - Debates of the Constitutional Convention: Vol. I "Supplemental Information Relating to the Convention and Journals of the Convention", December 1, 1967-February 9, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Debates of the Constitutional Convention: Vol. II "Journals of the Constitution", February 12-29, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - "Journals of the Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention", 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Reference Manual #1: The Convention, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Reference Manual #2: Constitutions of Pennsylvania and the United States, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Reference Manual #3: A History of Pennsylvania Constitutions, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Reference Manual #4: Local Government, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Reference Manual #5: The Judiciary, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Reference Manual #6: Legislative Apportionment, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Reference Manual #7: Taxation and State Finance, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Reference Manuals #8 and #9: Bibliography and Index, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Constitutional Proposals Adopted by the Convention, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 12)